Jelvin Base

https://jelv.in hi@jelv.in Manila, Philippines

WORK EXPERIENCE

PRODUCT MANAGER

MariaHealth (December 2019 – March 2020)

- Collaborating with developers & designers on day-to-day tasks
- Collaborating across teams to discover customer needs
- Creating experience experiments for sales and marketing
- Analyzing team performance and creating monthly internal reports
- Cascading and translating high level requirements to bite-sized tasks

LEAD UX DESIGNER

Make Technology (January 2019 – July 2020)

- Leading & collaborating with a team of multiple UX Designers
- Collaborating with team leads to discuss company growth & process improvement
- Collaborating with project managers & relaying tasks and deliverables to team members
- Proposing processes & systems to streamline operations
- Proposing business initiatives to refine internal business processes
- Facilitating goal setting sessions with team members to set KPI's
- Facilitating workshop for team members & interns
- Managing client & stakeholder expectations for multiple projects
- Facilitating design audits & review sessions with team members
- Writing content for the company process guidelines documentation
- Strategizing and creating content for marketing

UX DESIGNER

Make Technology (September 2017 – December 2018)

- Created user interface designs and mockups under different accounts
- · Created low fidelity mockups for user flows on multiple platforms
- Prepared high fidelity prototypes for usability testing
- Prepared research plans & conducting research activities
- Created design systems for better navigation in design projects
- Prepared handoff documentation for service and development
- Wrote case studies and articles for marketing and thought leadership
- Conducted user, market, & competitive research for brands & projects
- · Applied different processes with a major account in the company
- Collaborated with clients & stakeholders for certain projects
- Managed client expectations and setting sprint tasks developers

UI/UX DESIGNER, FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Proudcloud (November 2016 - August 2017)

- · Created user interface designs and mockups under different projects
- Collaborated with developers and stakeholders during design sprints
- Converted visual designs into working prototypes and front-end code
- Designed visual identities for products and services
- Prepared interaction design flows for user testing
- Conducted research on different approaches for better UX
- Organized and facilitate usability testing sessions with clients
- Handled and troubleshot UI related errors and inconsistencies

PROFILE

I'm a designer based in Manila and I handle graphic design projects with frequent coding in between if needed.

Not only am I enthusiastic about great user experience, I'm also keen in exploring different approaches for making processes more contextual and consistent.

Whenever I have spare time off from my usual work, I also accept freelance projects that involve custom lettering and calligraphy with the hopes of mastering the field of typography.

I have recently taken an interest in business as well and found the need to slowly integrate my work flow with an entrepreneurial perspective and mindset to further empathize with the clients that I work with.

SKILLS AND PROFICIENCY

In user interface design, I typically work on Sketch for layouts and mock-ups along with Adobe Illustrator if there's a need for vector graphics.

In coding and development, I mostly deal with Javascript and CSS for front end development work.

For visuals and graphics such as stock photography and illustration, I work on Adobe Lightroom and Adobe Photoshop respectively.

NOTES

Other freelance and unrelated work may be requested for reference.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER, GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Apical Design (February 2017 – June 2017)

- Designed the initial visual identity for the brand of the company
- · Created mockups of the website based on the visual identity
- Created user interface designs and layouts for web and mobile
- Developed mobile responsive pages from mockups to code

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PRODUCT DESIGNER

Senti Business Solutions, Inc. (November 2015 – July 2016)

- Handled front-end revisions of the company product Dashboard
- Created dynamic visualizations for collaborative projects
- Developed UI and data visualizations for the Dashboard
- Created an updated visual identity of the company
- Designed layouts and mockups based on the new visual identity
- Created digital assets for internals, marketing and social media
- Collaborated with developers on internal and external products

EDUCATION

BS COMPUTER SCIENCE - SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY

De La Salle University (June 2010 - December 2015)

- Worked as a Research Assistant for an inter-college thesis project
- Received Best Paper in Sustainability, Environment & Energy Proceedings during the DLSU Research Congress 2016
- Created a prototype for the collaborating organization of the thesis
- Received 2nd Honor Dean's List Award for Academic year 2013 2014
- Acting Web Manager for the school publication, The LaSallian